Hello and welcome to Real easyy English In this podcast we have real conversations in easyasy English to help you learn I'm Neil and I'm Becker you can find
A video version of this podcast along with a transcript to help you learn on our website PPclearningenglish.com. .
Hi Beckcca how are you I'm well thanks Neil how about you I'm pretty good today we're talking about phones now Becca how much time
Do you spend on your phone every day I don't know the number I haven't checked my screen time in a while
So your screen time is the time in which you spend looking on your phone screen.
Probably would guess that I spend quite a few hours looking at my phone How about you Yeah, I spend probably a lot of time on my phone every day and I'm not really happy about that.
Um because I think it's a waste of time, but I do it like millions of other people yeah, I mean phones can be very useful, you can get information very quickly.
Yes, this is true they are also really handy of course, for finding out information quickly and you can do loads
Of things that used to be quite hard to do.
Yeah, one of those things that we can probably do better with phones is to connect with people and to have contact with people, do you get lots of notifications from your friends and family on your phone?
Because I don't like spending too much time on my phone, I turned off my notifications now notifications are the little
Messages that you get from apps.
When people or the app wants to tell you something okay, so that's a good tip but really if you want to reduce your screen time is to turn off your notifications
Yeah I also.
Try not to doom scroll what what's doom scrolling that's probably how I spend a lot of time on my phone so when
You doom scroll you look at negative.
New stories or things that make you feel maybe a bit upset, a bit sad and you just keep scrolling and scrolling and scrolling and it really doesn't make
You feel good and so if you do, Like youbecca, a lot of doom scrolling,
That could be a sign of an addiction now an addiction is something that you can't stop doing.
So for example, an obvious example is smoking people who smoke, they have an addiction, it's something they have to do and we hear a lot.
About phone addiction and it's really hard to stop an addiction, even though I know doom scrolling is very bad for me and it doesn't
Make me feel good, I can't stop doing it.
I don't think you're alone Beckcca, but do you think most people look at their phone too much I do and I think that it doesn't matter.
How old you are I see phone addictions with people my age, people younger and people older,
I think that a lot of people are addicted to their phones Yeah, if you just look around anywhere most people,
Have their head down at that angle, looking at their phone, missing what's going on in the real world.
Okay, let's recap the vocabulary we learn in this episode first screen time and that's the time that you spend looking at an electronic screen we usually use
It to talk about looking at our phoneom scrolling scrolling is when you look one another after
Another after another and they're usually news stories Notifications are the messages that apps will you.
Make if something is an addiction it means that you can't stop doing it's it this week's episode of real.
And'll be.